Serhii Smyk

Sacramento, CA · smyk.serhi@gmail.com, serhismy@amazaon.com · http://smykserhi.com/ · https://www.linkedin.com/in/serhii-smyk-339097193/

Fully Work Authorized · No Visa Sponsorship Required · Open to Relocation

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 5 years of experience in UI development applications with React and other modern front end technologies using simple solutions for complicated problems. Experience in creating video streaming platforms like Netflix also skilled in different languages, git version control, unit testing and integration testing, strong computer science knowledge.

KEY SKILLS

- **Languages**: JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS3, HTML5, Java, C/C++,
- Frameworks: React, Node, Express, Meridian UI, Bootstrap, Material UI, Firebase, Selenium, JUnit, TestNG, Cucumber, Redux, Qt, ES6

- Bug Tracking: Postman, JMeter, JIRA
- Database: NoSQL, SQL, PostgreSQL
- English, Ukraine and Russian

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Cognizant(Amazon), Sacramento, CA

- Develop application using Amazon Web Services and Meridian UI components
 - Creating a module federated application with micro front end technology.

Front-End Developer

Code the Dream, Durham, NC

06/2020 - 05/2021

05/2021 - Present

- Develop responsive web pages and applications using React, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, Material-Ui, styled components, Bootstrap, React Hooks, HTML, CSS
- Build modular layouts, reusable code and libraries for future use
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders

Software Engineer in Test

01/2019 - 01/2020

CHI Software, Sacramento, CA

- Analyzed technical documentation for inconsistencies, ambiguities, contradictory requirements
- Designed and developed test systems, test cases and detail test scenarios with Maven and TestNG test automation system tool to make unit testing, increasing quality in first stage by 20%
- Analyzed requirements, procedures and problems to automate/improve existing Java Selenium test automation scripts systems
- Evaluated function and performance with performance testing system using JMeter and Postman

Software Developer

07/2016 - 01/2019

CHI Software, Kharkiv, UA

- Build, test, maintain and enhance front end development using the best practices and web standards in HTML, CSS, JavaScript ES6, REST and React
- Turning Photoshop mockups into robust web pages and other assets

Head of Customs Broker Department

02/2013 - 07/2016

Ferrytransservis LLC, Chernomorsk, Ukraine

International ferry logistics service in Black Sea with more than 100 employees

- \bullet Supervised customs clearance department, excluding unnecessary checking and as result decreasing customs clearance time by 40%
- Prepared contracts and related documentation according to strict standards, totaling more than \$500 million
- Facilitated customer issue resolution related to service performance and cargo issues

Customs Broker 09/2008 - 02/2013

EATC-Ukraine LLC, Chernomorsk, Ukraine

International logistics service

- Filled out declaration for customs clearing cargoes and goods
- Maintained open communication with customers and overseas partners to update parties on order changes

EDUCATION

Master of Science (MS), Electronic Engineering

Odessa National Polytechnic University, Odessa, Ukraine

Best technical university in southern Ukraine, member of the European University Association

Bachelor of Science (BS), Electronic Engineering

Odessa National Polytechnic University, Odessa, Ukraine

Best technical university in southern Ukraine, member of the European University Association

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Front-End Developer, Code the Dream, Durham, NC
- JavaScript, Udemy, San Francisco, CA, 2020
- QA Automation with Selenium WebDriver, Udemy, San Francisco, CA, 2019
- HTML5 + CSS3, Udemy, San Francisco, CA, 2019
- JAVA Developer, Hillel Computer School, Odessa, Ukraine, 2018
- C/C++ Developer, Hillel Computer School, Odessa, Ukraine, 2017

2008

2007